A Guide to the Records of the Governor's Special Advisor on Disability Issues in the Workplace, 2010-2013
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Governor's Special Advisor on Disability Issues in the Workplace, 2010-2013
The Library of Virginia
51127
XX cu. ft (XX boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Resources
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years (Code of Virginia 42.1-78). Restricted records in this collection have been flagged but not removed. Types of flagged information may include, but is not limited to: medical records, financial records, vital statistics records, personal information including Social Security numbers, Social Services records, juvenile court records, administrative investigation records, attorney-client privileged documents, personnel records, proprietary information, and terrorism information and response records. Some documents may be closed in their entirety, while others may allow for redaction.
Acquisition Information
Accession 51127 transferred by the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 8 January 2014.
Biographical/Historical Information
Ed Turner was appointed Special Advisor on Disability Issues in the Workplace in September of 2006. This position was located with the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human resources and served as a senior advisor to the Governor on disability employment policy. Turner served as the Governor's representative on disabily employment and community integration as part of the Olmstead Initiative and on the Virginia Disability Commission, and worked closely with the Senior Advisor for Workforce Issues. The special advisor also served as an advocate to advance disability employment and as a liaison to the disability community.
Scope and Content
Contains records created and maintained by Governor Kaine's Special Advisor on Disability Issues in the Workplace.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Supporting Documentation - Office of the Secretary, 2010-2011
Contents List
- Correspondence and subject files, 2006-2010.
  - Accessible Guide for Specialized Ground Transportation (Part I), undated. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accessible Guide for Specialized Ground Transportation (Part II), undated. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adult learning, 2008. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aging in Place Conference, 2007 June. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Association for People with Disabilities, 2008. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Association of University Affiliated Programs for Persons with Developmental Disabilities - Annual meeting, 1994 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), 1995-1997. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), 2006. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appointments, 2004-2005. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1995-2006. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Autism, 2006-2008. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Best Buddies of Virginia, 2007-2008. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Boards and Commissions, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brain injuries, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brookes Publishing, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Center for Independent Living - Training Conference, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chronic Disease Prevention and Control Conference, 2007 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - clothing, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Collaborations Conference, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Collaborations Conference, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Collaborations Conference, 2008. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - College of Direct Support, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Community Colleges, 2006-2007. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Community Development Corp., undated. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Connections Plus Consulting, Inc., undated. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence (Miscellaneous), 2005-2010. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - CPWG meeting, 2008 May. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Disability and Business Employment Technical Assistance Center, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Disability Rights Month, 2010. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Disability Services Board, undated. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Disability Services Board - Member Handbook, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Disaster Preparedness, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - DPN Project Leads - Administrative conference call, 2010 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Emergency Evacuation Training, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Planning meeting, 2009 May. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Emergency Preparedness, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Emerging issues, undated. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Empowering Customers with Disabilities (Presentation), 2006. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Endependence Center, 2006-2007. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Executive Directive 8 (Recruitment of Applicants with Disabilities), 2007. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Executive Order 2 (Emergency Planning and Preparedness), 2006. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General Assembly, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Governor's Forum on Disability and Economic Development, 2009 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Governor's Forum on Disability and Economic Development, 2009 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Governor's Housing Conference, 2009. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Grant work meetings, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Hanley meeting notes, 20. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - HIV prevention counseling, 2004-2005. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Homeland Security Strategy format, undated. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Human Resource Management, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Human Resources Leadership Conference, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Individual and Family Support Syndicate of Virginia - Retreat (1 of 2), 1994. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Individual and Family Support Syndicate of Virginia - Retreat (2 of 2), 1994. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Individual and Family Support Syndicate of Virginia, 1995. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Itineraries, 2006-2007. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Jackie Crews Award for Excellence in Leadership, 2005. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jackie Crews Award for Excellence in Leadership, 2006. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Labor, U.S. Dept. of, 2009. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Labor, Virginia Dept. of - High Growth Training Initiative grant, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Legislation, 2004. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - legislation, 2006. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - legislation, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Action Summary (SB 474 Certification of Sheltered Workshops), 2008. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Lists, 1998-2001. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Maximizing Potentials Conference, 1996. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2006-2010. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Money Follows the Person Workgroup, 2007 June 6. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Money Follows the Person Workgroup - Housing Task Force, 2007 June 20. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Money Follows the Person Workgroup, 2008 Feb-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Money Follows the Person Workgroup, 2008 June 27. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Money Follows the Person Workgroup, 2008 July 31. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Money Follows the Person Workgroup, 2008 Aug 12. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - National Center on Independent Living, 2006. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - National Cinemedia, 2009. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Council on Independent Living, 2006-2007. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Council on Independent Living, 2008. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - National Rehabilitation Association, 2003. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - National Rehabilitation Association, 2008-2009. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - National Spinal Cord Injuring Association, 2007. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - NTAR State Leadership Team - Meeting notes, 2009 Dec. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Nu Solutions, 2007. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Advisory Commission, 2006 Oct 31. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Advisory Commission, 2007 Mar 6. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Advisory Commission, 2007 May 22. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Advisory Commission, 2007 Oct 23. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Advisory Commission, 2008 Apr 1. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Advisory Commission, 2008 Oct 21. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Implementation Team, 2006 Oct 17. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Implementation Team, 2007 Mar 20. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Implementation Team, 2007 June 19. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Implementation Team, 2007 Sept 18. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Implementation Team - Housing and Transportation Small Group, 2007-2008. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Implementation Team - Housing and Transportation Small Group, 2007 Dec 11. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee, 2005. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Joint meeting of the CIAC and CIIT, 2005 May 24. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Joint meeting of the CIAC and CIIT, 2008 Sept 9. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Miscellaneous, 2005-2009. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Regional Disability Coalitions, 2007 June 19. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Olmstead Initiative - Strategic Plan, 2007. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - One Stop Career Center - Fact sheets (1-4), 2007. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Organizational chart (HHR), 2007 June. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets (miscellaneous), undated. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Parent Educational Advocacy Training Center, 2007. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Partners in Policy Making, 2006 Feb. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Partners in Policy Making, 2007 Mar. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Partners in Policy Making - The Nuts and Bolts of Developing and Giving Legislative Testimony, 2008 Mar. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Partnerships for People with Disabilities - Annual Report, 2008. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Peer counseling, 1985-1986. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Peninsula Center for Independent Living - Conference, 2006. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Presentation - Collaborations Conference, 2008 Oct. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Presentation - Living and Worshiping with People with Disabilities (Connections Plus Consulting), 2009 Apr. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Presentation - Partners in Policy Making Training, 2009 Mar. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Public-Private Partnerships, 2006-2007. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Quarterly report, 2006 Sept-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Reception with Lt. Governor Tim Kaine, 2005 Aug. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Rehabilitation and Social Services, Senate Committee on, 2009-2010. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Rehabilitation Research and Training Center (VCU), 1992-1994. (Box 9, Folder 2a)
  - Rehabilitation Research and Training Center (VCU), 2005. (Box 9, Folder 2b)
  - Rehabilitation Research and Training Center (VCU) - Business Roundtable meeting, 2007 Sept. (Box 9, Folder 2c)
  - Rehabilitation Research and Training Center (VCU) - Disability Awareness Training, 2003. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rehabilitation Research and Training Center (VCU) - Intineraries, 2005-2007. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Rehabilitation Research and Training Center (VCU) - Presentations, undated. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Research and Training Center on Independent Living, 2004. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Disability Services Board, 2008. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Roundtable Discussion - Expanding employment for adults with disabilities, 2009 Mar. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - School to Work Transition Service (DRS), undated. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Administration meeting, 2007 Nov. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Health and Human Resources - Agency head meetings, 2006-2007. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Self-Advocacy Training - Institute for Persons with Disabilities, 1999 Oct. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Sensitivity training, 1993. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Special Disability Advisor Position, 2010. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Special Education, undated. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute, 1998. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute, 1999. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute, 2000. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute, 2001. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute, 2002. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute - Mentor Program, 1997-1998. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute - Mentor Program, 2000. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Spinal Cord Injury Institute - Mentor Program, 2002. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - State Leaders Innovation Institute, 2009 Apr. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - State Use Program, 2006. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Summit on Disability Employment Policy, 2008 June. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Supported employment, 2005. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Tech Knowledgy, 2007. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Technical Assistance, 2003. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Testimony to General Assembly, 2010 Apr. (Box 11)
  - Transformation Leadership Team, 2006. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Transition Team - Office of Governor-Elect Tim Kaine, 2005. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Veterans, 2006-2007. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Veterans Workforce Development Task Force, 2007 Jan. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Violent offender registries, undated. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Virginia 2-1-1, undated. (Box 11, Folder 15)